Adriana Garzon Portela

San Jose, California | **Phone**: (415) 480 9060 | **Email**: adriana.garzon.portela@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/adriana-garzon-portela

Portfolio: https://www.adrianagarzonp.com

Summary

User experience and user interface designer with a background in graphic design and program management who is enthusiastic about creating meaningful and delightful user experiences. A self-directed learner and believer in life-long education and self-improvement. While gaining a certificate in UX/UI from UC Berkeley Extension, collaborated with teams face-to-face and remotely to redesign user experiences on a nonprofit and a government website. As an added bonus: Bicultural individual with native Spanish ability that translates into the capacity to understand diverse perspectives and think outside of the box.

Technical Skills

Technical: Figma, Adobe XD, Sketch, inVision, Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign | **UX/UI**: User research and testing, affinity mapping, persona creation, client journey mapping, user interface design, workflows, task-flows, paper-and-pencil to high fidelity prototypes

Projects

Pukka Trip - An app for travelers | Tools: Figma, Photoshop, Miro, and Procreate

- Implemented user-centered design methodology to uncovered pain points in the trip planning process of potential users and ideated solutions
- Created a high fidelity prototype of a mobile travel app that addresses user's pain points
- Prototype:

https://www.figma.com/proto/a5D3CdpMkvW74Vs1FdSmC4/PukkaTrip-V1.3?node-id=500% 3A21&viewport=649%2C286%2C0.11056149750947952&scaling=scale-down&hide-ui=1

National Park Service Redesign | Tools: Figma, Photoshop, Miro, Trello, and Google Drive

- Uncovered UI issues on the National Park Service site through usability testing
- Redesigned the site to improve the desktop and mobile experience for the user
- Desktop Prototype:

https://www.figma.com/proto/PMoiLekBVELpqQScBPSECT/National-Park-Service-Redesign?node-id=785%3A569&viewport=3708%2C156%2C0.2653471529483795&scaling=min-zoom&hide-ui=1

Mobile Prototype:

https://www.figma.com/proto/PMoiLekBVELpqQScBPSECT/National-Park-Service-Redesign?node-id=731%3A813&viewport=434%2C320%2C0.08525773137807846&scaling=scale-down&hide-ui=1

Experience

Graphic Designer, Jan. 2019 - Dec. 2019 Foothill College | Los Altos, CA

Collaborated with multiple stakeholders to create innovative visual designs that adhered to branding guidelines, were responsive to digital communication channels, and were effective in increasing student's participation in school activities.

- Used Adobe Photoshop, inDesign, Illustrator, Acrobat, Capture, and Procreate for digital and print designs
- Applied graphic and typographic principles of design as well as color theory to produce appropriate visual materials for clients
- Presented sketches and mockups to clients to help them visualize design ideas and incorporated their feedback effectively

Statewide Data and Evaluation Specialist, Sept. 2017 – Sept. 2019 Building Skills Partnership | San Jose, CA

Navigated time and financial constraints to ensure the appropriate selection and implementation of a CRM for the organization. Advocated for and supported the development of evaluation and data-driven decision-making processes.

- Based on user's feedback, developed visual paths on CRM to increase its usability
- Trained 25+ non-technical staff members on the use of the new technology including G-Suite, Salesforce, data-driven decision-making methodology
- Created 10 statewide and regional dashboards with meaningful data visualizations

Regional and Financial Education Program Coordinator, Dec. 2015 - Sept. 2017 Building Skills Partnership | San Jose, CA

Developed and executed an innovative plan to expand financial education and free tax preparation services by engaging funders and internal stakeholders in the design of client-centered offerings that alleviated common challenges related to participant's access and participation.

- Integrated financial capability offerings to free tax preparation sites; 35% of taxpayers saved part of their tax refund as a result of this initiative
- Pioneered integration of financial education and coaching offerings to worksite-based training; trained over 350 individuals in 2 years and provided case management and assistance to 50+ individuals seeking to achieve financial stability

Education

Bootcamp Certificate in UX/UI Design: UC Berkeley Extension | San Francisco, CA An intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to User Experience, User Interaction and Front-end Development. Skills learned consist of design thinking methodology, Figma, inVision, HTML5, CSS, User-Centric Design Research, Visual Prototyping & Wireframing, and User Interface Development.

Certificate in Graphic and Interactive Design: Foothill College | Los Altos, CA Skills learned consist of Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator, Adobe Acrobat, application of principles of design and typography.

Bachelor of Arts in Law: Externado University of Colombia | Bogotá, Colombia